[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a211", "question": "Who sang in a pop duo alongside Melanie Appleby?", "answer": "Kim Appleby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfeb", "question": "What type of foodstuff is traditionally eaten on Shrove Tuesday?", "answer": "Pancakes\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd467e347d002c297e4af", "question": "Who was the first monarch of the House of Windsor?", "answer": "George V", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf74", "question": "What sort of drink is Barbancourt?", "answer": "Rum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b787364247bf200fb873", "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "The Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b291", "question": "What Canadian territory came into existence on April 1, 1999?", "answer": "Nunavut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc05", "question": "Crusiverbalism refers to what activity?", "answer": "The creation or solving of crosswords", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339761", "question": "Which actress won an Oscar for her role in Monster's Ball?", "answer": "Halle Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddf166ce05a3942286dae", "question": "In which year was Tiger Woods named the PGA Tour Rookie of the Year?", "answer": "1996", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20e", "question": "What is Jason Voorhees' signature weapon?", "answer": "Machete", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec24c58dc25ca9e12ef63a", "question": "What was the very first Andrew Lloyd Webber musical to be adapted to film?", "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c607", "question": "The Asteroid Belt can be found between which two planets?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8f", "question": "What does \"J.R.R.\" stand for in J.R.R. Tolkien's name?", "answer": "John Ronald Reuel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7427a9e54d890926f6f3", "question": "In what country would you find geoglyphs known as the Nasca Lines?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaec", "question": "What is the capital of Tanzania?", "answer": "Dodoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a628", "question": "Which US state is home to Hot Springs National Park?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c223", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c171", "question": "What is the alternative name of scallions?", "answer": "Spring onions or green onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3b", "question": "Which element appears seventh on the periodic table?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a1586c0f9723ab15cb38", "question": "Which US president's Secret Service code name was Lancer?", "answer": "John F Kennedy's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d5", "question": "Speed Skating originated in which part of the world?", "answer": "Scandinavia and Northern Europe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6cd", "question": "What game awards the Stanley Cup?", "answer": "Ice hockey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a523", "question": "What is the capital of Lithuania?", "answer": "Vilnius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523dca736d4be723796b48", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a9", "question": "Who had the job of eliminating maverick androids?", "answer": "Blade runners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d19", "question": "In what country was composer Ludwig van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339487", "question": "Who played the role of Archie Leach in the 1988 movie \"A Fish Called Wanda\"?", "answer": "John Cleese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977f", "question": "What Canadian actor starred in Airplane! as Dr. Shirley Rumack?", "answer": "Leslie Neilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a97dc61d1b4d384d5d689", "question": "In mythology which giant made of bronze guarded Europa of Crete?", "answer": "Talos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea45e4ff048f679a45ab9b", "question": "Dimples on golf balls help increase speed by reducing what?", "answer": "Drag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d823745b36be73039d9", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9f", "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339244", "question": "What movie was hyped: \"Girls like me don't make invitations like this to just anyone\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec33fe83fe1f2a824bfc", "question": "What was the name of the earliest form of paper currency?", "answer": "\"Flying Money\" -- used during China's Tang dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69d", "question": "What animal is also known as an earth pig, antbear, or Cape anteater?", "answer": "Aardvark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa2", "question": "What musical won the Tony Award for Best Musical in 1996?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart Gets an 'F',\" what sickness does Lisa have?", "answer": "Mumps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73a", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sunflower State\"?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339376", "question": "In the movie \"Batman\", who claims to weigh 108 lbs?", "answer": "Vickie Vale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51d", "question": "In the field of medicine, what does MRI stand for?", "answer": "Magnetic Resonance Imaging", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339543", "question": "Who hosted \"The Hollywood Squares\" between 1986 and 1989?", "answer": "John Davidson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86a", "question": "Which Bay is located to the north of Spain?", "answer": "Bay of Biscay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5971e13f89261e916c8e09b3", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a0", "question": "What country is called, in its native language, \"Bharat\", after its legendary founder?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d077ab870e6f05ba600866", "question": "Which private eye character did the author Raymond Chandler create?", "answer": "Philip Marlowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa5e36ce05a3942286ec5", "question": "What real American Revolution battle served as inspiration for the film \"The Patriot?\"", "answer": "The Battle of Cowpens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbef76ce05a3942286ef9", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Heart of Glass\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdeb", "question": "What Burlingame, California, company was founded in 1984 to provide blood and urine analysis to athletes?", "answer": "BALCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e9", "question": "The first American blood bank was established in 1937 in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2a", "question": "The Bren light machine gun originated in which then country?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9c", "question": "What are the six weapons in a standard game of Clue?", "answer": "Candlestick, Lead Pipe, Knife, Revolver, Rope, and aWrench", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d92", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Artis Ivey?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d1", "question": "How did Norman E. Shumway make medical history?", "answer": "He performed the first successful transplant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012187f63c99d48cd169af3", "question": "What was Hugh Hefner\u2019s jet plane named?", "answer": "Big bunny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b647", "question": "What brand was famous for its Little Liver Pills?", "answer": "Carter's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bd", "question": "The Mario villain \"Wario\", made his first appearance in which Nintendo game?", "answer": "Super Mario Land 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b8d3e662d71a53651028", "question": "The \"clocks were striking thirteen\" at the start of which dystopian novel?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f14a9a72b906b34e3d03", "question": "What kind of animal is a bantam?", "answer": "Chicken -- A true bantam is a breed of chicken that is naturally small.  The male has a reputation for being very aggressive.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b133", "question": "What Roman committed suicide in 30 BC after hearing a false report on Cleopatra's death?", "answer": "Marc Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe4bd247818f5674af01b4", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a3", "question": "When was actress Diane Keaton born?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a990", "question": "What city named its airport after Galileo Galilei?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339443", "question": "Which Bond actor won an Academy Award for his role in \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f7fa01dd7bf43be5e83b", "question": "Aichmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Needles or sharp objects", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f0", "question": "What must a Las Vegas blackjack dealer do when they reaches 16?", "answer": "Take a card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c6", "question": "What hurricane devastated Charleston, South Carolina in 1989?", "answer": "Hugo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c88e59122f44c2d77a29c3d", "question": "Statefarm uses what NFL quarterback in their 2018 commercials?", "answer": "Aaron Rodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339011", "question": "Which famous painting was stolen from an Oslo museum in 1994?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7ddbff048f679a45ac00", "question": "Anthropophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "People or society", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a1", "question": "Which literary bear got its name from a London railway station?", "answer": "Paddington Bear", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02f", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", what pool game does Stewie play with Helen Keller?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d6", "question": "What New York City avenue divides the east side from the west side?", "answer": "Fifth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133953c", "question": "What soap opera was on air from 1952 until 2009?", "answer": "Guiding Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b57", "question": "Which movie studio has a roaring lion as its logo?", "answer": "MGM", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc4", "question": "Which Italian city was severely damaged by an earthquake in 1908?", "answer": "Messina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a790", "question": "What country lies on Israel\u2019s northern border?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b3", "question": "The Linke Scale is used to measure the blueness of what?", "answer": "The sky", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f1b301dd7bf43be5e807", "question": "Denim is the official fabric for which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc12d0469bb8041d07a07d", "question": "What direction should you stir your Christmas pudding according to tradition?", "answer": "East to West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51c95ff04d658268c9318", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8e", "question": "What Beatles song repeats the title in the lyrics forty-one times?", "answer": "Let It Be", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339923", "question": "What was the name of the high school in the movie \u201cGrease\u201d?", "answer": "Rydell High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df7", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Zeus?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a6", "question": "How many years after the American Revolution ended did the French Revolution begin?", "answer": "6", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14140b0ee8c595b6d39a2", "question": "What did Pablo Picasso protest in his \"Guernica\" masterpiece?", "answer": "The Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1cefc7bd84c0ea43ad43d", "question": "\"The Obvious Child\" was a 1990 hit for whom?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590720743745b36be73039f1", "question": "What do all the victims in the 1984 film \"Don\u2019t Open Till Christmas\" all have in common?", "answer": "They were wearing Santa Claus suits or items of clothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4be", "question": "When did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "June 29, 1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5921fcfba4edfd43a087adc7", "question": "What number is represented by \"M\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "1,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8d25ec223966ae8f884f", "question": "Who said this in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"? \"Hope is a dangerous thing. Hope can drive a man insane.\"", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e3f4ae5cb9e8bda6821369", "question": "Approximatly when did construction of the Colosseum finish?", "answer": "80 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a082", "question": "On what date did Bob Barker retire from hosting \"The Price is Right\"?", "answer": "June 15, 2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecc", "question": "Where was South Africa's Freedom Charter signed?", "answer": "Kliptown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef597d6ce05a3942286e04", "question": "How old was Miley Cyrus when she first auditioned for the role of \"Hannah Montana\"?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a7e49076251badbeab7", "question": "What was former US President William Taft\u2019s pet cow named?", "answer": "Pauline", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e6", "question": "On what sea is the Crimea?", "answer": "Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ca97877e98cb97778a07", "question": "Which city is Seattle's sister city in Japan?", "answer": "Kobe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddd", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"pundit\"?", "answer": "Hindi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfc", "question": "In France, what is called \"pain perdu\"?", "answer": "French toast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b246", "question": "The US's first law school for women was named for what cross-dressing Shakespearean character?", "answer": "Portia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b69912de762b54eb9be9417", "question": "What was the name of the album the band TLC released in 2013?", "answer": "20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d3", "question": "Which US state, one of the original 13 colonies, has a flag featuring an anchor surrounded by 13 stars?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa78", "question": "What major mountain ranges are located in New York State?", "answer": "Adirondack, Catskill, and Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa43a1c73aa70ea0b70b18", "question": "Which African city is famous for its native penguin population?", "answer": "Cape Town, South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58be2cb48faf425cf37add77", "question": "In what country would you find \"The Strand Arcade\", a covered shopping destination?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ef", "question": "How many red stripes are there on the American flag?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339540", "question": "What show is \"The end of something simple. And the beginning of everything else\"?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4de", "question": "What fruit comes in Hass and Florida variety?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd972b223c87fd04dd15e53", "question": "Who was the Egyptian deity of cats?", "answer": "Bastet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd55cec223966ae8f88d0", "question": "\"You\u2019re gonna need a bigger boat\" originated in what movie?", "answer": "\"Jaws\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339876", "question": "Trigun, a popular western sci-fi anime, consisted of how many episodes?", "answer": "26", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a829", "question": "What is the only New England state with no Atlantic coastline?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1b31f6756c9b30ba14f6", "question": "On which river is the city of Mandalay situated?", "answer": "Irrawaddy River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc0", "question": "Who met longtime best friend Gayle King in 1976?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b82", "question": "How many symphonies did Ludvig van Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339452", "question": "What were the children allergic to in the movie \"The Others\"?", "answer": "Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f71c1a9e54d890926f6e5", "question": "Texas is home to the longest-running what?", "answer": "State fair -- Lasting 24 days, the Texas State Fair is one of Dallas's most popular events.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa5", "question": "What country produces Angostura Bitters?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a5", "question": "Which penguin sex is larger?", "answer": "Males", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3d", "question": "The 2002 film \"Confessions of a Dangerous Mind\" was based on the unauthorized autobiography of what former gameshow host?", "answer": "Chuck Barris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff145cab0ee8c595b6d39bb", "question": "Richard Bachman is a pen name used by which American author?", "answer": "Steven King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50a", "question": "What country do the Galapagos Islands belong to?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec9", "question": "\"Dig 'em Frog\" was the mascot for which Kellogg's breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Honey Smacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25b", "question": "Which English county was Alfred Hitchcock born in?", "answer": "Essex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d73", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"Life Among the Lowly\"?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6017373744491cbd7c5a1786", "question": "What is the name of the iron-clad ship that engaged the CSS Virginia during the American Civil War?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the CSS Virginia engaged the USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe0", "question": "What was the name of Juliet's cousin killed by Benvolio in \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Tybalt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76f54eec85e375820b2e7", "question": "Where can you find the iconic Apollo Theater?", "answer": "Harlem, New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8a", "question": "A statue of Billy Bremner stands outside the ground of which football stadium?", "answer": "Leeds United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efc", "question": "What TV show opened with a \"control voice\" saying, \"Do not attempt to adjust the picture\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0f", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Gideon Fell?", "answer": "John Dickson Carr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febad6c7e83c707845b20f3", "question": "What is the technical term for jet lag?", "answer": "Desynchronosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a04fcad1ec93f27df769", "question": "What is Cask ale sometimes referred to as in the UK?", "answer": "Real ale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e7b506d333868d34d741", "question": "In 1929, what did Clarence Birdseye introduce?", "answer": "Frozen food", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65c541f3c0ead6880d612", "question": "What was the most important celestial object for the Aztecs?", "answer": "The sun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59decf64ea2747c8aff16d1e", "question": "Junko Tabei was famous for being the first woman to do what?", "answer": "Reach the summit of Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eba", "question": "What happens to Neo twice in a row that clues Trinity in to a glitch in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "A black cat passes him", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b719", "question": "What carol contains the words \"Fa-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la\"", "answer": "Deck the Halls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017401844491cbd7c5a17ba", "question": "Who was the only one of Henry VIII\u2019s wives to receive a Queen\u2019s funeral?", "answer": "Jane Seymour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6c", "question": "What was the name of the 80\u2019s band formed by Roland Orzabal and Curt Smith?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b821e662d71a5365101d", "question": "What do \"Peter Pan\" author J.M. Barrie's initials stand for?", "answer": "James Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936b", "question": "How many Oscar nominations did the 2002 movie \"Chicago\" receive?", "answer": "Thirteen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25f", "question": "What is Jane Fonda's middle name?", "answer": "Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09e", "question": "How many gallons does a \"half butt\" barrel contain?", "answer": "63", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad9", "question": "In 1997, what country singer formed the band, The Ranch, with two fellow Australian musicians?", "answer": "Keith Urban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6a37e83c707845b216b", "question": "Which actor committed himself to solitary confinement in order to prepare for his role in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a700", "question": "Which US state is home to Great Sand Dunes National Monument?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2bf", "question": "What split up into Gondwanaland and Laurasia?", "answer": "Pangaea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523d60736d4be723796b41", "question": "What is Canada\u2019s motto?", "answer": "From Sea to Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6f18a9e54d890926f6ce", "question": "What color are gondolas required to be painted in Venice?", "answer": "Black -- A 17th century doge's decree dictated that all gondolas must be painted with six coats of black paint.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d116fb4fea7fe947a22275", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c159", "question": "What is a Hurdy-Gurdy?", "answer": "Stringed instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a719", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Gem State\"?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397eb", "question": "Which famous duo also recorded under the name \"Tom and Jerry\"?", "answer": "Simon and Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ec", "question": "How many US states end with the letter \"O\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7ec3bb24f84e0b9f9ffe5", "question": "The \"Atomium\" landmark is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef92cd6ce05a3942286e87", "question": "Which famous actor was orginally offered the role of Tommy Williams in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea45b7ff048f679a45ab97", "question": "How many joules make one calorie?", "answer": "4.184", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bcf7877e98cb97778950", "question": "How are U-shaped valleys formed?", "answer": "Ice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a242", "question": "At the end of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\", what character stayed in Korea?", "answer": "Maxwell Q. Klinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389cd", "question": "What literary character is adopted by Messua and her husband who believe him to be their long-lost sibling?", "answer": "Mowgli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5db03eddaa1c9af2684d79a5", "question": "In the classic fighting game series \"Street Fighter\", what does the move \"Shoryuken\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Rising Dragon Punch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24b", "question": "What is the name of Bryan Adams' third studio album, released in 1983?", "answer": "Cuts Like a Knife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd0", "question": "What was discovered in Sutter's Mill in California in 1848?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523ec4736d4be723796b53", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96fae23c87fd04dd15e44", "question": "Which Christmas song was actually written for Thanksgiving?", "answer": "\"Jingle Bells\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cca", "question": "What kind of gem is El Corazon which is \"romanced\" in the movie \"Romancing the Stone\"?", "answer": "An emerald", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0e", "question": "Filmmaker Duncan Jones is the son of which British Glam Rock legend?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339953", "question": "What is the name of the skunk in \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Flower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b0", "question": "What river forms most of the border between the US states Georgia and Alabama?", "answer": "Chattahoochee river", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac83", "question": "Which Indian prime minister was assassinated by two of her bodyguards?", "answer": "Indira Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d1", "question": "The song \"A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes\" was originally featured in what Disney film?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab5", "question": "What brand of cognac calls itself \"Le Cognac de Napolean\"?", "answer": "Courvosier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c773", "question": "What animal species coined a phrase describing very cold temperatures?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a055", "question": "What 1977 film directed by and starring Ron Howard shares its name with a video game series?", "answer": "Grand Theft Auto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338986", "question": "What name is given to the overweight boy with glasses in the book \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Piggy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92b", "question": "What article of attire is known as a \"corset\" around police precincts?", "answer": "Bulletproof Vest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e439fcbed638185eaa26", "question": "What is the most visited attraction in New York City?", "answer": "The Metropolitan Museum of Art", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9693a23c87fd04dd15e08", "question": "The first Nobel Prize was awarded in which country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3b", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 501?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47051f8e329de4f877890", "question": "Which cricketer is known as \"The Cat\"?", "answer": "Phil Tufnell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b5", "question": "How many strings does the common Bass guitar have?", "answer": "4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff142dfb0ee8c595b6d39af", "question": "In 1905, Pablo Picasso entered his \"Rose Period\", painting jugglers and acrobats from where?", "answer": "Circus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a77a20565ad31a57c7e9", "question": "What Christmas tradition possibly came from the Pagan festival Saturnalia?", "answer": "Kissing under the mistletoe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e48", "question": "What word do we derive from the Salish Indian word for \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c51", "question": "Who starred in the lead male role in the 1968 movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6b720565ad31a57c7dd", "question": "The aircraft carrier USS Lexington was lost in which World War II battle?", "answer": "The Battle of the Coral Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e3", "question": "What was W. C. Fields' birth name?", "answer": "William Claude Dukenfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76685eec85e375820b282", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cd7424f0f7a362efd542", "question": "How man men have walked on the moon as of December 31, 2018?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b372481c3f17ccc40c8e22", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedddea6ce05a3942286da8", "question": "Which actress claims she cried when she was shown her wardrobe for the role of the monarch in the 2006 film \"The Queen\"?", "answer": "Helen Mirren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4a5fa5fdd6dd25324e2", "question": "What is the capital of Central African Republic?", "answer": "Bangui", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f4f301dd7bf43be5e826", "question": "What is the point at which two lines meet to form an angle?", "answer": "Vertex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8fb7401dd7bf43be5e852", "question": "What is brandy?", "answer": "Distilled wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012150063c99d48cd169ae5", "question": "Einstein won the 1921 Nobel Prize for Physics for explaining what?", "answer": "Photoelectric effect -- However, that did not stop him from giving a lecture\u00a0on relativity in his acceptance speech.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bd", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 515?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd0", "question": "The group ABBA hails from what European country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59b", "question": "What Canadian province is home to Pink Mountain, Muncho Lake and Nootka Sound?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8591ec223966ae8f8807", "question": "Who directed both \"Frankenstein\" and \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "James Whale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2d", "question": "Who was William Shakespeare's wife?", "answer": "Anne Hathaway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0e386fcbed638185eaa22", "question": "What U.S. state is nicknamed \"The Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d75", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Parish Boy's Progress\"?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c6749076251badbead3", "question": "In the U.S., the 1920s were often described by what term?", "answer": "The roaring twenties ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a20", "question": "Who portrayed Michael Corleone's second wife in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff08fd2e662d71a53650fb2", "question": "Which philosophical movement helped inspire the American Revolution?", "answer": "The Enlightenment -- It included great leaps in philosophical thought \u2014 including ideas about democracy, the social contract, and freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5ed26ce05a3942286e3a", "question": "What baseball legend has a cameo in \"The Benchwarmers\"?", "answer": "Reggie Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a96", "question": "\"The Tortelli's\" was the first attempt at a spin-off from what TV show?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b34f", "question": "Who did Zola Budd trip in the 1984 Olympics?", "answer": "Mary Decker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aea", "question": "What classic 1933 horror film's last line is, \"It was beauty who killed the beast\"?", "answer": "King Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3b", "question": "What plant is used to make tequila?", "answer": "Blue agave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f5f2cee580c7f8fd1e5b", "question": "Where did the deadliest airline disaster occur?", "answer": "Tenerife", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ab", "question": "Kansas City is built at the confluence of what two rivers?", "answer": "Kansas River and Missouri River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a8", "question": "Who wrote the novel 1984?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e5bffe83fe1f2a824bc4", "question": "In the Bible, Jesus referred to the disciples James and John as Sons of whom?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa29", "question": "In what Indian city is the Taj Mahal located?", "answer": "Agra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338917", "question": "Who wrote \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5da", "question": "What does M&M stand for?", "answer": "Mars & Murrie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede44d6ce05a3942286ddb", "question": "What song by The Four Tops has the lyric \"Sugar pie honey bunch\"?", "answer": "\"I Can't Help Myself\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1802baab681b09292186", "question": "Which car design firm was responsible for the design of the Enzo Ferrari?", "answer": "Pininfarina", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1dc", "question": "What are the two main ingredients of a Hollandaise sauce?\u00a0", "answer": "Egg yolks and liquid butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c23e877e98cb97778987", "question": "The \"nene\" is the official bird of which state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be65", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"double-eagle\" on a gold hole?", "answer": "An albatross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bec", "question": "What musical featured \"I Could Have Danced All Night\"?", "answer": "My Fair Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad60", "question": "The 2008 Summer Olympic Games were held in what city?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323315bf195a31e15d7397", "question": "Blitz, Boondock, Bristol, Scrunge and Squop are terms used in what game?", "answer": "Tiddlywinks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c184", "question": "Heliophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Sun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7f", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dragon Seed\"?", "answer": "Pearl S. Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e63", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Mr. Magoo?", "answer": "Jim Backus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7e", "question": "How many dogs survived the sinking of the Titanic?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9c", "question": "Who wrote \"Around the World in Eighty Days\"?", "answer": "Jules Verne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70d", "question": "What is the name given to glittery strings hung on Christmas trees?", "answer": "Tinsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339263", "question": "What was the title of the 2006 \"Casino Royale\" theme sung by Chris Cornell?", "answer": "You Know My Name", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9cd", "question": "In which continent would you find the Mackenzie river?\u00a0", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed7", "question": "What kind of animal's kidnapping is solved in \"Ace Ventura: Pet Detective\"?", "answer": "A dolphin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cb", "question": "Who won an Oscar for \"Best Actress\" for her role in \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c690", "question": "What fraction of the Earth's gravity is the moon's?", "answer": "One sixth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd9de7e83c707845b217e", "question": "In the game of golf, the iconic \"Green Jacket\" is presented to the winner of which championship?", "answer": "Masters Tournament", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339617", "question": "Adam West portrayed which superhero on television?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb1", "question": "In 1926, the funeral of what silent movie star attracted a crowd of nearly 100,000 people to view the remains?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd07", "question": "What hockey great wore the number 68 to commemorate the Prague Spring of 1968?", "answer": "Jaromir Jagr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1e25b5a031299b74573f", "question": "Which present-day country in the Southern hemisphere did the Dutch reach in 1606?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927a", "question": "Which member of the Quack Pack in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" did not make it to the final?", "answer": "Britney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390be", "question": "What character is writer Colin Dexter most famous for creating?", "answer": "Inspector Morse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078a310eee65b76b9f265f", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf53", "question": "What is the main ingredient in Borsch?", "answer": "Beetroot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e20", "question": "What popular movie website took its name from a John Travolta line in the movie \"Broken Arrow\"?", "answer": "Ain't It Cool News", "category": "entertainment"}]